A Guide to the Michael Collins Papers, 1907-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- SERIES III. PROJECT APOLLO, 1966-2004
  - Apollo 11
    - Apollo 11 twenty-year anniversary
      - Materials Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Lunar Landing-Folder 1 (Box-folder 35-37)
      - Materials Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Lunar Landing-Folder 2 (Box-folder 35-38)
      - Materials Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Lunar Landing-Folder 3 (Box-folder 35-39)
      - Materials Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Lunar Landing-Folder 4 (Box-folder 35-40)
      - Materials Commemorating the Twentieth Anniversary of the Lunar Landing-Folder 5 (Box-folder 35-41)
    - Apollo 11 twenty-five-year anniversary
      - 25th Anniversary of the Lunar Landing- Folder 1 (Box-folder 37-1)
      - 25th Anniversary of the Lunar Landing- Folder 2 (Box-folder 37-2)
    - Apollo 11 thirty-year anniversary (Box-folder 37-3)
    - Apollo 11 thirty-five year anniversary
      - 35th Anniversary of the Lunar Landing Press Kit (Box-folder 37-5)
      - 35th Anniversary of the Lunar Landing Correspondence, Articles, and Speeches (Box-folder 37-4)
    - Apollo 11 ticker tape parade photo - New York City, August 13 1966 (Box-folder 34-2)
    - "Zeus's Brothers" - poem by Rod C. Teter (Box-folder 34-3)
  - NASA Materials
    - Memoranda
      - Memos (1964) (Box-folder 38-32)
      - Memos (1965-1969) (Box-folder 38-33)
    - "NASA Astronauts" booklet (1967) (Box-folder 35-27)
    - "Mission H-1 Abort from Lunar Powered Descent and Subsequent Rendezvous," November 7 1969 (Box-folder 13-1)
    - Program for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration's Annual Honor Awards Ceremony, November 13, 1970 (Box-folder 38-41)
    - Chain of Command at NASA (Box-folder 38-5)
    - International Responses to NASA (Box-folder 38-6)
- SERIES IV. ASSISTANT SECRETARY OF STATE, 1969-1971
  - Correspondence, notes, and photographs,1961-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 18-1)
  - Printed materials, 1969-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 18-2 (2 folders))
  - Reel-to-Reel Audio, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 18-3 (2 folders))
    - Television appearance, November 26 1969
    - Television news, November 28 1969
    - "Washington Week," November 29 1969
    - Swearing-in ceremony, January 6 1970, [2 copies]
    - "Washington Week," January 10 1970
    - Television appearance, April 16 1970
    - Television appearance, February 3 1971, [2 copies]
    - Unidentified recording
- SERIES V. NATIONAL AIR AND SPACE MUSEUM, 1971-1979
  - Memoranda, photographs, and ephemera, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 18-4 (2 folders))
  - Newsclippings, 1971-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 18-5 (3 folders))
  - "NASM Press Clippings, 1976-1977" booklet, 1977 (Box-folder 18-6)
  - Regents dinner and Collins' farewell reception [audiocassette recordings], January 1978, [2 items] (Box-folder 18-7)
  - NASM Interview (Box-folder 35-29)
  - National Air and Space Museum Articles and Memos (Box-folder 35-30)
- SERIES VI. BOARDS AND CLUBS, 1973-1989
  - Air and Space Heritage Council, 1984 (Box-folder 19-1)
  - Andrulis Research Corporation, 1985 (Box-folder 19-2)
  - CPRW Inc., 1985-1986 (Box-folder 19-3 (2 folders))
  - First Flight Society, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 19-4)
  - International Academy of Astronautics, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 19-5)
  - International Aerospace Hall of Fame, 1971-1988 (Box-folder 19-6)
  - International Platform Association, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 19-7)
  - Metropolitan Club (Washington, D.C.), 1980-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 19-8)
  - NASA Goals Task Force, 1986-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 19-9 (2 folders))
  - National Aeronautic Association, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 19-10)
  - National Research Institute for Neural Injury, 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 19-11)
  - National Space Club, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 19-12)
  - Space-Public Corporation, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 19-13)
  - Space World, 1988 (Box-folder 19-14)
  - U. S. Global Strategy Council and World Strategy Network, 1982-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 19-15)
  - Materials from Various Organizations of Which Michael Collins Was a Member (Box-folder 36-22)
- SERIES VII. WRITINGS, 1908-2004
  - Carrying the Fire (Book)
    - Incoming correspondence, 1972-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 20-1)
      (includes correspondence from from Charles Lindbergh)
    - Outgoing correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20-2)
    - Notes, legal agreements and background materials, 1971-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 20-3)
    - Typescript draft (Box-folder 20-4 (3 folders))
    - Condensed versions, 1975 (Box-folder 20-5)
      (Reader's Digest and USIA)
    - Publicity, 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 20-6)
    - Reviews, 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 20-7 (2 folders))
    - Excerpt in Air and Space (October/November 1987) (Box-folder 35-4)
    - Excerpt in Science Digest (January 1975) (Box-folder 36-38)
    - Excerpts in Smithsonian (July 1974) (Box-folder 36-39)
    - Materials Concerning the Book Release (Box-folder 35-16)
    - Reader's Digest- Excerpt from Carrying the Fire (January 1975) (Box-folder 35-32)
    - Book Background Material- Folder 1 (Box-folder 38-7)
    - Book Background Material- Folder 2 (Box-folder 38-8)
    - Book Background Material- Folder 3 (Box-folder 38-9)
    - Book Background Material- Folder 4 (Box-folder 38-10)
    - Preface Research (Box-folder 38-11)
    - Chapter One Research (Box-folder 38-12)
    - Chapter Two Research (Box-folder 38-13)
    - Chapter Three Research (Box-folder 38-14)
    - Chapter Four Research (Box-folder 38-15)
    - Chapter Five Reasearch (Box-folder 38-16)
    - Modified Chapters Six-Seven Research (Box-folder 38-17)
    - Old Chapter Six-New Eight Research (Box-folder 38-18)
    - Old Chapter Seven-New Nine Research- Folder 1 (Box-folder 38-19)
    - Old Chapter Seven-New Nine Research- Folder 2 (Box-folder 38-20)
    - Chapter Ten Research (Box-folder 38-21)
    - New Chapter Eleven Research (Box-folder 38-22)
    - New Chapter Twelve Research (Box-folder 38-23)
    - Chapter Thirteen Research (Box-folder 38-24)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 38-25)
  - Flying to the Moon and Other Strange Places (Book)
    - Typescript draft (Box-folder 20-8)
    - Notes and reviews, 1975-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 20-9)
    - Miscellaneous Materials (Box-folder 35-20)
    - Book Reviews, Invoices, and Correspondence (Box-folder 38-4)
  - Liftoff! (Book)
    - Correspondence and notes, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 21-1)
    - Notes / background material, 1908-1986
      - Introduction, 1987-1988, n.d. (Box-folder 21-11)
      - Chapter 1, 1957-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 21-12 (2 folders))
      - Chapter 2, 1961-1971 (Box-folder 21-13)
      - Chapter 3, 1908-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 21-14 (2 folders))
      - Chapter 5, 1969-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 21-15)
      - Chapter 6, 1976-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 21-16 (4 folders))
      - Chapter 7, 1977-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 22-1)
    - Interview notes, 1985-1987, n.d.
      - Maxime Faget (Box-folder 21-2)
      - Robert Gilruth, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 21-3)
      - John Glenn (Box-folder 21-4)
      - Caldwell Johnson, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 21-5)
      - Chuck Mathews, 1986 (Box-folder 21-6)
      - Thomas Paine, 1986 (Box-folder 21-7)
      - Laurence Weeks (Box-folder 21-8)
      - John Yardley, 1985 (Box-folder 21-9)
      - Skylab and ASTP crews (Box-folder 21-10)
    - Typescript draft, c. 1987
      - Chapter 1, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-2)
      - Chapter 2, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-3)
      - Chapter 3, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-4)
      - Chapter 4, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-5)
      - Chapter 5, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-6)
      - Chapter 6, c. 1987 (Box-folder 22-7)
    - Rewrite notes and background material, 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 22-8)
    - Proofs, 1988 (Box-folder 22-9)
    - Publicity, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 22-10)
    - Reviews, 1988 (Box-folder 22-11)
    - Galley proofs with revisions (Box-folder 34-5)
    - Final galley proofs with comments on illustrations (Box-folder 34-6)
  - Mission to Mars (Book)
    - Criticism of Mission to Mars (Box-folder 36-4)
    - Materials for Preface to Mission to Mars (Box-folder 36-14)
    - Mars Illustrations (Box-folder 36-15)
    - Misc. Correspondence, Notes, and Images for Mission to Mars (Box-folder 36-16)
    - Mission to Mars-Book Reviews, Correspondence, and Materials from the Book Tour (Box-folder 36-17)
    - Copy of Manuscript: Part 1 (Box-folder 36-18)
    - Copy of Manuscript: Part 2 (Box-folder 36-19)
    - Mars Atlas (Box-folder 38-3)
    - NASA Transparencies (Box-folder 38-36)
  - Articles
    - "Spaceport, U.S.A.," 1985 (Box-folder 23-1)
    - "Into the Unknown," 1987 (Box-folder 23-2)
    - "Flying High, Flying Low," 1988 (Box-folder 23-3)
    - "Mission to Mars" in National Geographic (November 1988) (Box-folder 36-21)
    - "A New Look at the National Air and Space Museum Smithsonian Institution" Aerospace Historian (Spring, March 1972) (Box-folder 35-2)
    - "Reflections of an Apollo 11 Astronaut" Air and Space (Fall 1982) (Box-folder 35-3)
    - "The Garden of Earth" in Guideposts (March 1971) (Box-folder 35-22)
    - Cricket Magazine (1978) (Box-folder 35-13)
    - "The Hairy Ride Aboard Gemini 10, a 'bridge' on our way to the moon" in Smithsonian (May 1988) (Box-folder 35-35)
    - "Aerospace on the Mall" in Aerospace (June 1973) (Box-folder 36-25)
    - Commercial Space magazine (1985) (Box-folder 36-28)
    - "Mars Bound" in Final Frontier (March/April 1991) (Box-folder 36-29)
    - Geo (February 1978) (Box-folder 36-31)
    - Geo (August 1981) (Box-folder 36-32)
    - "Out to Launch: Kennedy Space Center and Cape Canaveral" in National Geographic Traveler (Spring 1986) (Box-folder 36-34)
    - "Showing Lindbergh the Air and Space Museum" in Saturday Review (April 16, 1977) (Box-folder 36-36)
    - Article About the Space Shuttle in Smithsonian (May 1977) (Box-folder 36-37)
    - Other articles, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 23-4)
      - "Aerospace on the Mall," 1973
      - "An Astronaut Comes Down to Earth," 1974
      - "Carrying the Fire: the Fire Carrier Tells It Like It Is," 1974
      - "Reflections of a Space Adventurer," 1974
      - "Thoughts from Space," 1974
      - "An Apollo Astronaut Addresses the Question of Man vs. Machine," 1985
      - "The Hairy Ride Aboard Gemini 10: a 'Bridge' On Our Way to the Moon," 1988
      - "At Home in Space"
      - "A Homecoming" in St. Albans Bulletin (Winter 1970) (Box-folder 35-36)
      - Interview with Michael Collins- US News and World Report (May 16, 1988) (Box-folder 35-42)
      - Articles About Michael Collins' Life After Apollo 11 (Box-folder 38-2)
      - Miscellaneous Short Articles Concerning Michael Collins (Box-folder 36-27)
      - "Where to Now?" Interview with Michael Collins in the G.A.O. (Winter 1988-1989) (Box-folder 36-30)
      - "Moon Landing was a Hoax" in Weekly World News (March 5, 1991) (Box-folder 37-8)
    - Book reviews, 1970-1987 (Box-folder 23-5)
      - A World of My Own, 1970
      - The Heavens and the Earth, 1985
      - Entering Space, 1985
      - Sphere, 1987
      - Voyager, 1987
      - Various Book Reviews by Michael Collins (Box-folder 35-9)
  - Other Writings (Drafts, Forwards/Prologues, Notes)
    - Air University Review Aerospace Medicine (July-August 1968) (Box-folder 35-5)
    - Articles About Michael Collins, Buzz Aldrin, and Neil Armstrong (Box-folder 35-6)
    - Blue Planet (Fall 2001) (Box-folder 35-7)
    - The Explorers Journal (Spring 2004) (Box-folder 35-15)
    - "The Moon: How Far is It...to Charles Lindbergh?" by Rober Baehr published in American Studies in Transition (Box-folder 35-26)
    - Sky and Telescope (June 1985) (Box-folder 35-34)
    - Naples Daily News-Saturday, February 24, 2007, c. 2007 (Box-folder 38-38)
    - Newspaper Clippings on NASA Astronauts (Box-folder 38-39)
    - Sky and Telescope Magazine (November 1991), c. 1991 (Box-folder 38-44)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1969-1988 (Box-folder 23-7)
      (includes report for Rogers Commission and foreword for The Space Shuttle: a Quantum Leap by George J. Torres)
    - Book Forward for Milestones of Aviation
    - The Day Gravity Stopped-Draft of a Children's Book by Michael Collins (Box-folder 35-17)
    - Introduction to the Smithsonian book of Spaceflight (Box-folder 35-23)
    - Space Machines Notes (Box-folder 35-28)
    - Short Pieces Written by Michael Collins (Box-folder 35-32)
    - "An Approach to Space Logistics" presentation (Box-folder 36-26)
    - National Geographic Eyewitness to the 20th Century- Contributions by Michael Collins (Box-folder 36-33)
    - Prologue to Blueprint for Space by Fred Ordway (Box-folder 36-35)
    - Drafts of Articles and Speeches by Michael Collins- Folder 1 (Box-folder 37-6)
    - Drafts of Articles and Speeches by Michael Collins- Folder 2 (Box-folder 37-7)
    - "CSIS Resources, Technology, and Future Battlefields" (Box-folder 38-26)
    - Draft of "Factor A-Understanding the Requirement" (Box-folder 38-29)
    - Miscellaneous Lectures (Box-folder 38-31)
    - Quotations (Box-folder 38-43)
    - Short Writings by Michael Collins (Box-folder 38-46)
    - Opinion / editorial pieces, 1971-1987 (Box-folder 23-6)
- SERIES VIII. SPEECHES, 1970-1996
  - January 1970 (Box-folder 24-1)
    - Assistant secretary of state swearing-in, January 6 1970
    - Seminar on Foreign Policy, January 26 1970
  - February-April 1970 (Box-folder 24-2)
    - National Association of Sunday School Teachers, February 11 1970
    - Hubbard Medal presentation, February 16 1970
    - Maryland-Delaware-D.C. Press Association, February 21 1970
    - National Association of Independent Schools, March 7 1970
    - Oakton High School (Vienna, Virginia), April 29 1970
  - May 1970 (Box-folder 24-3)
    - Robert J. Collier Trophy presentation, May 6 1970
    - 25th anniversary of V-E Day, May 7 1970
    - Association of Industrial Advertisers, May 11 1970
    - Kansas Bankers Association, May 22 1970
  - June-December 1970 (Box-folder 24-4)
    - Stonehill College, June 7 1970
    - St. Michael's College, June 8 1970
    - Northeastern University commencement, June 14 1970
    - Aspen Country Day School, September 8 1970
  - January-February 1971 (Box-folder 24-5)
    - Binational Center (Mexico City), January 28 1971
    - World Affairs Council (Pittsburgh), February 9 1971
    - World Affairs Council (Los Angeles), February 23 1971
  - March-November 1971 (Box-folder 24-6)
    - Film showing at William A. M. Burden residence (Florida), March 28 1971
    - Brief Board of Regents on National Air and Space Museum, September 27 1971
  - December 1971 (Box-folder 24-7)
    - Men's Luncheon Group (Smithsonian Institution), December 9 1971
  - 1972 (Box-folder 24-8)
    - NASM Advisory Board, January 18 1972
    - Air Force Association "Comfort Silver" Awards, September 13 1972
    - "Early Birds of Aviation," September 22 1972
    - USAF Academy Planetarium special program, October13 1972
    - USAF Brief Smithsonian council on NASM construction, November 10 1972
    - Vance Air Force Base graduation, November 25 1972
  - 1973 (Box-folder 24-9)
    - Aviation / Space Writers Association, June 11 1973
    - Combined Federal Campaign / Keymen luncheon, October12 1973
    - Elkins Airport dedication, November 17 1973
  - 1974 (Box-folder 24-10)
    - Military Order of the World Wars, March 14 1974
    - Smithsonian Institution luncheon with museum director, March 28 1974
    - U. S. Pavilion (Spokane, Washington), July 4 1974
    - NASM Advisory Board, July 25 1974
    - Death of Charles Lindbergh, August 26 1974
  - 1975 (Box-folder 24-11)
    - Concern benefit, March 13 1975
    - Summer Series Institute (Xavier University), June 12 1975
    - National Board of Smithsonian Associates, October15 1975
    - Southeastern University, October22 1975
    - Fairchild Conference at Cal Tech, August 8, 1975 (Box-folder 36-7)
  - 1976 (Box-folder 24-12)
    - Lindbergh Forum, January 21 1976
    - Screen News Digest Tribute to Robert Goddard, February 10 1976
    - Achievement Rewards for College Students, March 10 1976
    - Tribute to Robert Goddard, March 16 1976
    - "Your Senator Reports" television show with Senator Charles H. Percy, June 21 1976
    - National Youth Science Camp, June 30 1976
    - Wells Fargo Bicentennial Awards, September 4 1976
    - Junior Officer Council (Columbus Air Force Base), October28 1976
  - 1977 (Box-folder 24-13)
    - NASM Advisory Board, February 24 1977
    - Werner von Braun memorial service, June 22 1977
    - Dedication of Delta Solar Sculpture (Venezuela), June 29 1977
    - ADS Reserve (Wright-Patterson Air Force Base), August 1 1977
    - Society of Experimental Test Pilots, October14 1977
  - 1978 (Box-folder 24-14)
    - American University Speakers Weekend, February 23 1978
    - Dinner honoring Barry Goldwater, March 13 1978
    - AIAA Houston Chapter, March 21 1978
    - Mrs. Carter's luncheon for wife of Rumanian president, April 13 1978
  - January-June 1979 (Box-folder 24-15)
    - Einstein centennial reception, March 2 1979
    - Senate of Scientists, March 14 1979
    - "Joys of Research" Colloquium, March 16 1979
    - William James Forum (Washington College), April 18 1979
    - Brewer Trophy presentation, April 21 1979
    - Dedication of multiple mirror telescope (Tucson, Arizona), May 9 1979
  - July-December 1979 (Box-folder 24-16)
    - Tactical Training Wing (Holloman Air Force Base), October13 1979
  - January-June 1980 (Box-folder 25-1)
    - Pax River, April 18 1980
    - Virginia Mason Research Center, April 24 1980
    - Republican Platform Committee of Republican National Committee, May 8 1980
  - July-October 1980 (Box-folder 25-2)
    - Aeronautical Engineering Duty / Aeronautical Maintenance Duty Symposium, October3 1980
    - Symposium on Space Activities and Implications (McGill University), October16 1980
  - November-December 1980 (Box-folder 25-3)
    - Military Order of the Carabao, November 21 1980
  - 1981-1984 (Box-folder 25-4)
    - George Washington University, January 29 1981
    - NCMA (Langley Air Force Base), March 19 1981
    - Lees McRae College, March 30 1981
    - Kennedy Library, May 10 1981
    - South Africa, 1982
    - Young Astronaut Program, October17 1984
    - US Air Force-Squadron Officer School Space Symposium, May 9, 1984 (Box-folder 36-24)
  - January-June 1985 (Box-folder 25-5)
    - AT & T Information Systems, January 8 1985
    - IBM, January 16 1985
    - Greater Bangor Chamber of Commerce, January 25 1985
  - July-December 1985 (Box-folder 25-6)
    - National Aviation Hall of Fame (Dayton, Ohio), July 19/20 1985
    - Washington College, September 19 1985
    - Borg-Warner (Parkersburg, West Virginia), October22 1985
  - January-April 1986 (Box-folder 25-7)
    - Young Harris College, January 15 1986
  - May-June 1986 (Box-folder 25-8)
    - Boca Raton College, May 17 1986
    - Symposium "The Economic Payback from Space" GWU, July 16, 1986 (Box-folder 36-6)
  - July-December 1986 (Box-folder 25-9)
    - Fairmont State College, August 18 1986
    - BeA Fasteners, October18 1986
    - Coffeeville Community College, November 18 1986
  - January-June 1987 (Box-folder 25-10)
    - 25 Years of Man in Space (University of Rome), March 9 1987
    - AIAA / NASA / USAF Symposium on Automation, Robotics and Advanced Computing for the National Space Program, March 11 1987
    - Hartford Graduate Center, April 1 1987
    - Kobe Space and Science Center, May 5 1987
    - LTV Steel sales seminar, May 13 1987
  - July-December 1987 (Box-folder 25-11)
    - The Bon, November 21 1987
    - "Star Wars," c.1987
  - 1988
    - Ethics of Change Conference (Atlantic Center for the Arts), February 19 1988 (Box-folder 25-12)
    - Atlantic Center for the Arts, February 19, 1988 (Box-folder 36-1)
    - First in Flight Society, December 17, 1988 (Box-folder 36-8)
  - 1989
    - Chautaugua, 1989 (Box-folder 36-2)
  - 1990
    - Heavenly News Conference-National Cathedral Association, January 6, 1990 (Box-folder 36-10)
    - IBM Speech, January 11, 1990 (Box-folder 36-11)
    - International Conference on Aerospace History, April 23-27, 1990 (Box-folder 36-12)
  - 1991
    - Eastern Secondary Mortgage Market Conference, September 23, 1991 (Box-folder 36-5)
    - NASM- From Vinland to Mars, October 9, 1991 (Box-folder 36-20)
  - 1994
    - Tenth Annual Bakersfield Business Conference, October 15, 1994 (Box-folder 36-23)
  - 1996
    - Lindbergh Lecture (May 9, 1996) (VHS), c. 1996 (Box 37)
    - NASM-Lindbergh Lecture (May 9, 1996) (Box-folder 38-37)
  - Undated
    - Michael Collins Speech 2 (VHS) (Box 37)
- SERIES IX. CORRESPONDENCE, 1963-1973
  - Personal Correspondence,1963-1973 (Box-folder 25-13)
    (includes letters from Buzz Aldrin, Charles Lindbergh and Lyndon B. Johnson)
  - Correspondence with Chelsea House Publishers (Box-folder 36-3)
  - Email From Kate Doolan to Ed White, November 24, 2000 (Box-folder 35-14)
- SERIES X. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL, 1966-2003
  - Calendars
    - Calendar for 1964 (Box-folder 35-10)
    - Calendar for 1965
    - Calendar for 1966 (Box-folder 35-12)
  - Interviews and Television Appearances
    - Johnson Space Center Oral History Project, c. 1998 (Box-folder 36-13)
    - A Chautauqua Chronicle (VHS) (Box 37)
    - American News Women's Club-Michael Collins (May 8, 1991) (VHS), c. 1991 (Box 37)
    - Newton's Apple-Rich and Famous (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Newton's Apple-Gore, Collins, R, and F (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Kennedy Space Center-Roll 40 Michael Collins Interview #1 (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Kennedy Space Center-Roll 41Michael Collins Interview #2 (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Kennedy Space Center-Roll 42 Michael Collins Interview #3 (VHS) (Box 37)
    - For All Mankind (VHS) (Box 37)
    - Society of Experimental Test Pilots- 2003 Centennial of Flight Oral History Sessions (DVD), c. 2003 (Box 37)
  - Photographs and Published Materials
    - Printed materials and photographs,1966-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 25-14)
    - Photographs of Michael Collins (Box-folder 35-31, Box-folder 38-42)
- SERIES XI. HONORS AND MEMORABILIA, 1961-1989
  - Certificates and accompanying material, 1969-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 25-15 (2 folders))
    - First Life Astropolicy in the World, July 16 1969
    - Souvenir plot of land - Stratford-upon-Avon, July 25 1969
    - Pierre Guzman Prize, October29 1969
    - Order of Leopold, November 5 1969
    - Doctor of Laws - Saint Michael's College, June 7 1970
    - Doctor of Science - Northeastern University, June 14 1970
    - International Academy of Astronautics, December 31 1972
    - Apollo Lunar Science Community, March 5 1973
    - Military Order of the World Wars, March 14 1974
    - Advanced Management Program - Harvard University, December 19 1974
    - National Space Club, March 12 1975
    - Order of Rio Branco, July 29 1975
    - Doctor of Science - Southeastern University, October22 1975
    - National Civil Service League, November 16 1976
    - Legion of Merit, March 11 1977
    - Aviation / Space Writers Association Distinguished Public Service Award, 1977
    - Federation Aeronautique Internationale Gold Medal, 1977
    - for Senior Government Executives on Public Policy Issues, December 1978
    - American Astronautical Society John F. Kennedy Astronautics Award, March 30 1979
    - Air Reserve Forces Policy Committee, June 30 1979
    - Spirit of St. Louis Medal, November 19 1980
    - Lees-McRae Monogram Club, March 30 1981
    - Doctor of Astronautical Science - Salem College, July 20 1982
    - National Aviation Hall of Fame, July 1985
    - Texas Medal of Honor
    - Articles and Correspondence Concerning Various Honors and Awards Bestowed Upon Michael Collins (Box-folder 35-23)
    - Honorary Doctorate for Michael Collins from Stonehill College (Box-folder 38-30)
  - Paperweights
    - Project Gemini, c. 1966 (Box-folder 26-1)
    - Fiat car, September 10 1969 (Box-folder 26-2)
    - Aircraft joystick (Box-folder 26-3)
  - Plaques